# Daniel A. Pinedo

### Management Operations & Strategy, R&D

**\** 213.999.5619

@ daniel.pinedo@cgu.edu

% pinedo.org

### **SUMMARY**

Management strategist specialized in inclusion within the global workforce, human capital strategy, and operations of machine assisted cognition and decision-making in management. Recent applied experience in creating bleeding-edge selection tools for Fortune 100 Best Company that incorporates machine-learning technology into decision-making. Strong background in research methods and statistical methods that translate and transfer into management contexts of operations and strategy. Leadership coach that brings focus, deep listening, and relational mindfulness practice that nurtures strengths, resilience, and insights in client interactions.

# **STRENGTHS**



### Strategic

Knowing and implementing multiple solutions in real-time



### Individualization

Finding and matching the strengths of others



#### Relator

Helping others achieve their goals



#### Learner

Improving and gaining new skills



### Ideation

Connecting with concepts and people

# **ABILITIES**



Performance Monitoring & Evaluation



**Coaching & Mentoring** 



Talent Research & Development



**Talent Management** 



**Nurturing Inclusive Culture** 



**Operations & Strategy** 

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Research Associate

### **Accenture PLC, Talent Innovation Lab**

## 11/2018 - Current

Member of Research and Development Lab in partnership with Claremont Graduate University for global HR strategy in consulting firm with a global workforce size of 500,000+. Lab project management style was agile and iterative. Projects included:

- PROJECT 1: Literature Review for statistical analysis of future job candidates in Volatile, Uncertain, Complex, and Ambiguous (VUCA) world - led to Project 2.
- PROJECT 2: Methods expert in creation of interview protocol and items for VUCA analysis; deliverable presented for implementation to senior global management team; Implementation plan initiated led to Project 3.
- PROJECT 3: Subject matter expert for creation of validated scoring measure for VUCA interview protocol; consulted regional employee
  experience teams for initial stages of pilot for interview protocol with goal for global implementation IN PROGRESS

### **EXPERIENCE**

### **External Consultant**

#### **ICM Partners**

Part of a course-based project for one of the largest creative talent agencies in the world. HR department is in the process of restructuring with recent hiring of CHRO.

- 150 + employees participated in organizational diagnosis of assistant agent job design and agent leadership development that provided insights into specific discrepancies in how agents and assistants give and receive job feedback.
- 1-year development plan presented to CHRO with training cost savings projected to be \$10-\$15,000 per new assistant in year one.

#### Lecturer

#### **Mount Saint Mary's University**

**1** 01/2016 - 05/2018

% msmu.edu

Undergraduate contract faculty position in psychology department. This role included teaching courses in Research Methods, Social Psychology, and Organizational Psychology; academic counseling, and administration.

- Led undergraduate research colloquium every semester for five consecutive semesters. Increased participation of students by over 300%, started intra-department faculty collaboration, and turned the event from internal-only attendance of 5-10 guests to a public facing event with over 50 guests.
- Academic counseling for 15 students on an ongoing basis including: tracking graduation requirements, course selection, career counseling, monitoring degree progress, and crisis counseling. 100% graduation rate of advisees.

### Clinical Psychologist Intern

#### **Sovereign Health Group**

**1** 08/2014 - 08/2015

Clinical work in an inpatient facility providing individual and group therapy, psychological assessment, and internal organizational consulting services.

Assisted program director in streamlining management of distribution of caseload to employees, leading to 25% increase in overall
revenue by increasing cases per employee, and increasing insurance billing overall.

## Manager / Interim Director

### Sofia University Electroencephalography Lab

**1** 09/2012 - 06/2013

% sofia.edu

Academic EEG lab specialized in physiological correlates of meditative states, event-related potentials, and brainwave analysis.

- created training program for graduate students with four paid positions for training in using EEG equipment and running experiments with human subjects.
- Researched potential grant funding totally \$500,000, and reported updates of grant-writing weekly to the office of the provost.

# **Teaching Assistant**

#### Institute of Transpersonal Psychology (Sofia University)

mm 09/2011 - 12/2012

% sofia.edu

Teaching assistant to Dr. Arthur Hastings, faculty of research methods for PhD psychology program.

 Graded papers, co-taught, and provided office hours for assistance to doctoral students in Doctoral Research Seminar (FA11-12), and Doctoral Thesis Seminar (SP12)

### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Network Operations Engineer**

#### **Oversee**

**10/2007 - 08/2008** 

% oversee.net

Network operations for website portfolio company. Role was mission critical as network infrastructure was primary revenue generation avenue of company.

- Responsible for entire revenue-generating network infrastructure of \$100 million company, with 100% compliance of service level
  agreements for all internal clients within company.
- Oversaw 2 catastrophic network outages due to developer deployment errors and ensured mitigation of downtime to under 10
  minutes in both cases, including physical access to co-located network infrastructure
- · Responsible for debriefing CTO in each outage case.

# **EDUCATION**

#### 

### MA Clinical Psychology

#### **Sofia University**

#### BA

#### **Naropa University**

# **TECHNOLOGIES**

### **Programming**

R SPSS C++ Python LaTeX

#### **Statistics**

ANOVA Multiple Regression Social Network Analysis Psychometric Network Analysis

Categorical Data Analysis Non-Parametric Data Analysis